<simplesect id="config-theme-explanation" xreflabel="theme explanations">
  <?dbhtml filename="explanation.html" dir="config"?>
  <title>Attribute names used, explanations, possible values, examples</title>

  <screen>Name            Example(s)
|               | Possible values (if not obvious)
|               | | Explanation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
"pixels"
                "2"

                    An integer, amount of pixels.


"size"
                "2x2"

                    Pixels vertically times pixels horizontally.


"percent"        
                 "87"

                    Any percent value from 1 to 100.

"toggle"         
                 "true"

                    sets a value as true (1) or false (0).


"padding"
                "2 2 2 2"

                    Free pixels from top, free pixels under, free pixels from left, free pixels from right.


"decorname"
                "DEFAULT"

                    Any name for a decoration set, special decoration set names are:

                  DEFAULT,

                    Defines decorations to all windows unless overridden with another decoration set (REQUIRED).

                  MENU,

                    Defines decorations for menus.

                  STATUSWINDOW,

                    Defines decorations for the status window (REQUIRED).

                  CMDDIALOG,

                    Defines decorations for the command dialog.

                  WORKSPACEINDICATOR,

                    Defines decorations for the workspace indicator.

                  BORDERLESS,

                    Defines decorations for borderless windows (recommended).

                  TITLEBARLESS,

                    Defines decorations for titlebarless windows (recommended,
                    should be there if your theme looks nasty when toggled titlebarless).


"colour"
                "#FFFFFF"

                    A colour value in RGB format.

"imagename"
                "topleftcorner.png#fixed"

                    Image files filename with one of these possible variables:

                  #fixed,

                    Image is fixed size. Default if omitted.

                  #scaled,

                    Image will be scaled to fit the area it's defined for.

                  #tiled,

                    Image will be repeated as many times as needed to fill the area it's defined for.


"texture"
                "Solid #888888 1x1"

                    Any valid texture. Valid textures are:

                  EMPTY,

                    No texture (transparent).

                  SOLID colour size,

                    A solid colour texture of defined colour and size.

                  SOLIDRAISED colour colour colour pixels pixels toggle toggle toggle toggle size,

                    A solid colour texture with a 3D look of defined colours, form and size.

                    First colour defines the main fill colour, second the hilight colour used on the left and top
                    parts of the texture, third the hilight colour on the bottom and right parts of the texture.

                    First pixel amount defines how fart apart the 3D effects are from eachother, second pixel
                    amount is how thick the bordering will be (both pixels default to 1).
                    
                    The four toggles are used to tell which raised corners are to be drawn. This is usefull for
                    example when defining solidraised frame corner pieces. The order is Top, Bottom, Left, Right
                    (not unlike that used in padding). As example: "True False True False" (or 1 0 1 0) could
                    mean you want to draw the TopLeft piece of a solidraised window border.

                    Size should explain itself, see above.

                  IMAGE imagename,

                    An image texture using the defined imagename


"fontstring"
                 "XFT#Verdana:size=10#Left#1 1"
                 "-misc-fixed-*-*-*-*-14-*-*-*-*-*-*-1#Center#1 1"

                    Defines a font. Chopped to parts by # marks.

                    First the font name, then the text orientation, then shadow offsets,
                    then font type if not traditional x font. Some fields can be omitted.


"buttonactions"
                 "1" { Actions = "Close" }

                    Buttonactions work alike what you are used from the mouse config, first mouse button number
                    pressed when this action should happen, then any standard pekwm actions.</screen>

</simplesect>

