<simplesect id="config-theme-structure" xreflabel="theme structure">
  <?dbhtml filename="structure.html" dir="config"?>
  <title>Structure</title>

<screen>PDecor{}: the block for decoration sets, any amount of Decor sections can exist inside this block.

	Decor, decorname{}: name of the decoration set.


		Title{}: theming of the frame.

			Height, pixels

				Amount of pixels the titlebar should height.

			HeightAdapt, boolean

				If true, Height is adapted to fit the Title font.

			Pad, padding

				How many pixels are left around a title text.

			Focused, texture

				Background texture for a focused titlebar.

			UnFocused, texture

				Background texture for an unfocused titlebar.

			WidthMin, pixels

				Minimum width of title in pixels, will also place the titlebar outside of the window borders.
				Use 0 to place titlebar inside borders.

			WidthMax, percent

				Maximum width of titles relative to window width, when this value ends up being smaller than
				the value in WidthMin, WidthMin is overridden.

			WidthSymetric, toggle

				Set true to constant width titles or false to use titles that only are as big as the clients
				title text string requires (note, asymmetric width is not fully implemented yet, always set
				this true for now to avoid problems).


			Tab{}: theming of a titlebar tab.

				Focused, texture

					Background texture for a tab of a focused window.

				Unfocused, texture

					Background texture for a tab of an unfocused window.

				FocusedSelected, texture

					Background texture for the currently selected tab of a focused window.

				UnFocusedSelected, texture

					Background texture for the currently selected tab of an unfocused window.


			FontColor{}: theming of font colours

				Focused, colour colour

					Text colour for a tab of a focused window. second value is the shadow colour.

				Unfocused, colour colour

					Text colour for a tab of an unfocused window. second value for shadow.

				FocusedSelected, colour colour

					Text colour for the currently selected tab of a focused window. second value for shadow.

				UnFocusedSelected, colour colour

					Text colour for the currently selected tab of an unfocused window. second value for shadow.


			Font{}: theming of the titlebar fonts.

				Focused, fontstring

					Font of the text of a tab of a focused window.

				Unfocused, fontstring

					Font of the text of a tab of an unfocused window.

				FocusedSelected, fontstring

					Font of the text of the currently selected tab of a focused window.

				UnFocusedSelected, fontstring

					Font of the text of the currently selected tab of an unfocused window.


			Separator{}: theming of the tab separator.

				Focused, texture

					Separator texture for a focused window.

				Unfocused, texture

					Separator texture for an unfocused window.


			Buttons{}: theming of titlebar buttons.

				Right{}: places the button on the right end of the titlebar.
				Left{}:  places the button on the left end of the titlebar.

					Focused, texture

						Texture for button of a focused window.

					Unfocused, texture

						Texture for button of an unfocused window.

					Pressed, texture

						Texture for button that is pressed.

					Button, buttonactions

						Configures what to do when a button is pressed.


			Border{}: theming of the borders.

				Focused{}:   borders for focused windows.
				UnFocused{}: borders for unfocused windows.

					TopLeft, texture

						Texture for the top left corner.

					Top, texture

						Texture for the top border.

					TopRight, texture

						Texture for the top right corner.

					Left, texture

						Texture for the left border.

					Right, texture

						Texture for the right birder.

					BottomLeft, texture

						Texture for the bottom left corner.

					Bottom, texture

						Texture for the bottom border.

					BottomRight, texture

						Texture for the bottom right border.



Harbour{}: enables theming of the harbour.

	Texture, texture

		Texture to use as the harbour background.



Menu{}: themes the insides of a menu window.

	Pad, padding

		How many pixels of space around an entry is reserved.

	Focused{}:    apply these when the menu/submenu is focused.
	Unfocused{}:  apply these when the menu/submenu is not focused.
	Selected{}:   apply these on the menu entry currently selected.

		Font, fontstring

			What font to use.

		Background, texture

			A texture that starts from the top of the menu and ends on the bottom.

		Item, texture

			A texture that starts from the top of a menu entry and ends on the bottom of the entry.

		Text, colour

			Colour of text to use.

		Separator, texture

			Texture to use as separator (required, client menu will break if none is defined).

		Arrow, texture

			Texture to use for indicating submenus (you want this to be defined too).



CmdDialog{}: themes the insides of a command dialog window.

	Font, fontstring

		What font to use.

	Texture, texture

		Texture to use as the background.

	Text, colour

		Colour of text.

	Pad, padding

		Amount of pixels of space around font to reserve.



Status{}: themes the insides of the status window that shows up when moving windows and so on.

	Font, fontstring

		What font to use.

	Texture, texture

		Texture to use as the background.

	Text, colour

		Colour of text.

	Pad, padding

		Amount of pixels of space around font to reserve.



WorkspaceIndicator{}: themes the workspace indicator that shows up when switching workspace.

	Font, fontstring

		What font to use.


	Background, texture

		Background for the whole window.


	Workspace, texture

		Texture to use when rendering a workspace.

	WorkspaceActive, texture

		Texture to use when rendering the active workspace.

	Text, colour

		Colour of text.

	EdgePadding, padding

		Amount of pixels of space around window edges and workspaces.

	WorkspacePadding, padding

		Amount of pixels of space between workspaces.</screen>

</simplesect>
