<section id="config-theme-structure" xreflabel="theme structure">
  <?dbhtml filename="structure.html" dir="config"?>
  <title>Theme structure</title>
  <section>
    <title>PDecor</title>
    <para>
      The block for decoration sets, any amount of Decor sections can exist inside this block.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Decor</title>
      <para>A list of blocks with theme specifications the various types of decorations.</para>
      <section>
        <title>Title</title>
        <para>Theming of the frame.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Height (pixels): Amount of pixels the titlebar should height.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>HeightAdapt (boolean): If true, Height is adapted to fit the Title font.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Pad (pixels t,l,r,b): How many pixels are left around a title text.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Focused (texture): Background texture for a focused titlebar.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>UnFocused (texture): Background texture for an unfocused titlebar.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>WidthMin (pixels): Minimum width of title in pixels, will also place the titlebar outside of the window borders. Use 0 to place titlebar inside borders.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>WidthMax (percent): Maximum width of titles relative to window width, when this value ends up being smaller than the value in WidthMin, WidthMin is overridden.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>WidthSymetric (boolean): Set true to constant width titles or false to use titles that only are as big as the clients title text string requires (note, asymmetric width is not fully implemented yet, always set this true for now to avoid problems).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <section>
          <title>Tab</title>
          <para>Theming of a titlebar tabs.</para>
          
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Focused (texture): Background texture for a tab of a focused window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Unfocused (texture): Background texture for a tab of an unfocused window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>FocusedSelected (texture): Background texture for the currently selected tab of a focused window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>UnFocusedSelected (texture): Background texture for the currently selected tab of an unfocused window.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>FontColor</title>
          <para>Theming of font colors.</para>
          
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Focused (colour colour): Text colour for a tab of a focused window. second value is
                the shadow colour.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Unfocused (colour colour): Text colour for a tab of an unfocused window. second value
                for shadow.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                FocusedSelected (colour colour): Text colour for the currently selected tab of a
                focused window. second value for shadow.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                UnFocusedSelected (colour colour): Text colour for the currently selected tab of an
                unfocused window. second value for shadow.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Font</title>
          <para>Theming of the titlebar fonts.</para>
          
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Focused (fontstring): Font of the text of a tab of a focused window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Unfocused (fontstring): Font of the text of a tab of an unfocused window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                FocusedSelected (fontstring): Font of the text of the currently selected tab of
                a focused window.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                UnFocusedSelected (fontstring): Font of the text of the currently selected tab of an
                unfocused window.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Separator</title>
          <para>Theming of the tab separator.</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Focused (texture): Separator texture for a focused window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Unfocused (texture): Separator texture for an unfocused window.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Buttons</title>
          <para>Theming of titlebar buttons.</para>
          <section>
            <title>Right = "Name"</title>
            <para>Places the button on the right end of the titlebar.</para>
          </section>
          <section>
            <title>Left = "Name"</title>
            <para>Places the button on the left end of the titlebar.</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Focused (texture): Texture for button of a focused window.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Unfocused (texture): Texture for button of an unfocused window.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Pressed (texture): Texture for button that is pressed.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Hover (texture): Texture for button when pointer is placed on it.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>SetShape (bool): If true, the shape of the button is derived from the
                      alpha-channel. If false, the alpha-channel sets only the transparency.
                      (defaults to true)</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Button (buttonactions): Configures what to do when a button is pressed.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </section>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Border</title>
          <para>Theming of the borders.</para>
          
          <para>Focused: borders for focused windows.</para>
          <para>UnFocused: borders for unfocused windows.</para>
          
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>TopLeft (texture): Texture for the top left corner.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Top (texture): Texture for the top border.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>TopRight (texture): Texture for the top right corner.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Left (texture): Texture for the left border.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Right (texture): Texture for the right birder.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>BottomLeft (texture): Texture for the bottom left corner.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Bottom (texture): Texture for the bottom border.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>BottomRight (texture): Texture for the bottom right border.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Harbour</title>
      <para>Enables theming of the harbour.</para>
      
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Texture, texture: Texture to use as the harbour background.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Menu</title>
      <para>Themes the insides of a menu window.</para>
      
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Pad (padding): How many pixels of space around an entry is reserved.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section>
        <title>State</title>
        <para>
          One of Focused, Unfocused and Selected defining the appearance when the menu/submenu is
          focused, not focused and the menu entry currently selected.
        </para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Font (fontstring): What font to use.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Background (texture): A texture that starts from the top of the menu and ends on
              the bottom.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Item (texture): A texture that starts from the top of a menu entry and ends on the
              bottom of the entry.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Text (colour): Colour of text to use.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Separator (texture): Texture to use as separator (required, client menu will break if none is defined).</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Arrow (texture): Texture to use for indicating submenus (you want this to be defined too).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>CmdDialog</title>
      <para>Themes the insides of a command dialog window.</para>
      
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Font (fontstring): What font to use.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Texture (texture): Texture to use as the background.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Text (colour): Colour of text.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Pad (padding): Amount of pixels of space around font to reserve.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Status</title>
      <para>Themes the insides of the status window that shows up when moving windows and so on.</para>
      
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Font (fontstring): What font to use.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Texture (texture): Texture to use as the background.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Text (colour): Colour of text.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Pad (padding): Amount of pixels of space around font to reserve.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>WorkspaceIndicator</title>
      <para>Themes the workspace indicator that shows up when switching workspace.</para>
      
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Font (fontstring): What font to use.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Background (texture): Background for the whole window.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Workspace (texture): Texture to use when rendering a workspace.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>WorkspaceActive (texture): Texture to use when rendering the active workspace.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Text (colour): Colour of text.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>EdgePadding (padding): Amount of pixels of space around window edges and workspaces.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>WorkspacePadding (padding): Amount of pixels of space between workspaces.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>
