<simplesect id="usage-grouping-advanced" xreflabel="Advanced Grouping Topics"> 
	<title>Advanced Grouping Topics</title>
	<para>Another thing you can do with window grouping is Tagging. This
		is done by setting the toggleable attribute "tagged" on a frame with the action "Set Tagged".
		A tag is like a miniature autogroup. It says "All new windows launched should be
		automatically grouped to this Frame" and all other autogrouping defined
		in the autoproperties will be ignored while it is set.
		"UnSet Tagged" removes the tag. Default keybinding to toggle tagging
		on a frame is Ctrl+Mod1+T then T. Unsetting tagging works even if
		the window you have set tagged isn't active. It's default keybinding is
		Ctrl+Mod1+T then C.
	</para>
	<para>
		You can toggle all autogrouping on and off with the toggleable attribute GlobalGrouping.
		To disable you need to use the action "Unset GlobalGrouping" and to enable autogrouping
		use "Set GlobalGrouping". The default keybinding that toggless between set and unset is
		Ctrl+Mod1+T then G.
	</para>
	<para>
		You can set a marked state on clients with "set marked" and then attach those marked
		clients to another frame by focusing the frame you want the marked clients attached to
		and then using the AttachMarked action. By default marking can be reached with two
		simple keybindings. Mod4+Z toggles a clients Marked state and Mod4+A attaches clients
		with marked state set into the current frame. Marked clients will have "[M]" appended
		to their titlebars.
	</para>
	<para>
		Pekwm also includes some menus that have to do with grouping.
		AttachClientInFrame (Ctrl+Mod1+M, A) sends the current client to the selected frame.
		AttachFrameInFrame (Ctrl+Mod1+M, F) sends the contents of the current frame to the selected frame.
		AttachClient (Ctrl+Mod1+M, Shift+A) brings the selected client into the current frame.
		AttachFrame (Ctrl+Mod1+M, Shift+F) brings the contents of the selected frame into the current frame.
	</para>
</simplesect>

