<simplesect id="usage-gettingstarted-icons" xreflabel="About Menus and Iconification">
  <title>About Menus and Iconification</title>

  <para>
    When you Iconify (This is the traditional name in unix. Windows
    calls this minimizing.) a window in pekwm, it doesn't really go
    anywhere like you might expect. You can de-iconify using one of
    three menus: The Icon menu, the Goto menu, or the GotoClient menu.
    When you click on an item in one of these menus, it takes you to
    that window deiconifying when necessary.
  </para>

  <para>
    Icon menu shows you a list of all currently iconified windows.
    Use Mod4+Shift+I to bring it up.
  </para>

  <para>
    Goto menu shows you a list of windows currently active. This menu
    will only show the currently active window of possible window
    groups.  Use Mod4+L, or middle click of the mouse on the root
    window or screen edges to bring this menu up.
  </para>

  <para>
    GotoClient menu shows you a list of every window currently open.
    Window groups are separated from eachother with a menu separator
    wich is defined by the currently used theme, usually a line of
    some sort.  You need to be using window grouping to really see any
    difference between the GotoClient and Goto menus.  Use Mod4+C, or
    middle click of the mouse on the root window or screen edges while
    holding down Mod4 to bring up the GotoClient menu.
  </para>

  <para>
    An Item in the goto and gotoclient menu and icon menu (and attach
    menus) has the following syntax:
    <screen>&lt;number> [symbols] Window title</screen> The number
    represents what workspace the window is on. Symbols is a list of
    symbols that represent window states. They are:

    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Symbols in the pekwm menus</title>

      <listitem><para>* (sticky)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>. (iconified)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>^ (shaded)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>+ (above normal window layer)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>- (below normal window layer)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>A (active in group)</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>

  <note>
    <para>
      If you are using window grouping, the whole group will
      iconify instead of one window. Please ungroup before
      minimizing if you wish to iconify a single client window
      from a group frame.
    </para>
  </note>
</simplesect>

