<simplesect id="usage-gettingstarted-mouse" xreflabel="Using the mouse">
<title>Using the mouse</title>
<para>
Pekwm has excellent mouse support. Here you'll learn how to do some
usual window management actions using the default configuration.
</para>
<para>
Moving windows is rather easy and I think you already got the hang of
using the left mouse button on the titlebar and dragging. But did you
notice that when you press Mod1 while dragging on the client window
(not the titlebar) it works just as well.
</para>
<para>
Resizing is also easy and most are familiar with it. Hang on to a border
of the window with the left mouse button and drag. Release the button
and you're done. But what you likely didn't know is that if you press Mod1 and
then drag on the client window with the right mouse button it also
makes windows resize. Try it, it's great.
</para>
<para>
Minimizing (iconifying) with the mouse is possible thru the window menu.
Right click on a windows titlebar and select Iconify. Many themes also
implement a iconifying button on the titlebar. Also see <xref linkend="usage-gettingstarted-icons"/>.
</para>
<para>
Shading is done by double clicking the titlebar with the middle mouse button. Unshade doing it again.
</para>
<para>
Maximizing is quite easy. Hold Mod1 and double click with the left
button. Many themes also have a maximize button in them.
The default theme has one on the right corner of the titlebar.
It's also possible to use the window menu (right click on titlebar).
</para>
<para>
Filling. Sounds odd? Its not. It just means you can make a window grow as
large as it can until it hits the borders of the windows surrounding it.
Easy as pie, double click on the titlebar with the left mouse button.
Excellent feature you are likely to grow to like.
</para>
<para>
Raising windows. Easy. Left click on the windows titlebar or hold Mod1
and left click anywhere on the window.
</para>
<para>
Lowering windows. Hold Mod4 and left click anywhere on the window.
</para>
<para>
Closing. Most themes implement a close button. Default theme has one on
the left end of the titlebar. You can also close a client by holding
Mod4 and right clicking on its title. Note that the client doesn't have
to be the active client of the frame for this to work. Also see the
window menu.
</para>
<para>
Grouping. Middle click and drag on a titlebar and release over the frame
you want the window into. Holding Mod1 and middle clicking works on the
whole client window. This process can also be automated, more on that
later.
</para>
<para>
Activating clients. Now that you have multiple clients grouped into one frame,
you can switch between them simply by left clicking on the clients title.
Doing so also raises the frame. If you don't want the frame to raise,
middle click on the clients title. Also try turning the mouse wheel on a
frames titlebar when it has more than one client.
</para>
<para>
Menus. As mentioned, press the right mouse button on a windows titlebar
and you get the window menu. You can do lots of things from there that
are not possible by mouse shortcuts. To bring up the root menu (the one
you use to launch programs) click the right button on the background or
on the screen edges. To get the Goto menu, click the middle button on
the background or screen edges.
</para>
<para>
Most theme buttons work with a left click. Some also have specials when
you use other mouse buttons on them. Like the default themes maximize
button. Try it. The default themes close button also has a special when
you right click on it. With it it is possible to kill the client if it's
so stuck you can't close it normally.
</para>
<para>
That ends our short introduction to using the mouse in pekwm. Hope you
found the defaults pleasant to use. Remember that if you didn't like
something, you can change it. See <xref linkend="config-keys_mouse-mouse"/> for how.
</para>

</simplesect>

